http://www.nais.org/about/legal-and-privacy-information/

NAIS Career CenterDASLDirectoriesParents' GuideTrustees' Guide
Participate
Close
Participate
Conferences
Annual ConferencePeople of Color Conference CASE-NAIS Independent Schools Conference
Institutes & Workshops
Diversity Leadership InstituteInstitute for New HeadsLeadership Through PartnershipInclusive Schools Network InstituteEquity Design LabSchool Leadership Team Experience School Leadership Institute
Fellowship for Aspiring School Heads
Sponsorship & Advertising
Learn
Close
Learn
Independent Ideas Blog
Independent School MagazineFall 2020:Volume 80 Number 1
Independent TeacherFall 2020:Volume 18 Number 1
Principles of Good Practice (PGPs)
Resource Guides
Start StrongPromote Great GovernanceGrow EnrollmentCultivate Diverse and Inclusive CommunitiesEnsure Financial SustainabilityRecruit and Retain Top TalentLead Through ChangeBuild an Effective TeamCreate Inspiring Places to LearnManage a Crisis Fund the Future
Knowledge Center
Legal and Legislative Resources
NAIS Legal News You Can Use NAIS Legal Advisories
Research Clearinghouse
NAIS Podcasts
Member Voices The Trustee Table
NAIS Bulletin
Inspiration Lab
Community Market
Analyze
Close
Analyze
Data and Analysis for School Leadership (DASL)
About DASLSchool SurveysDemographicsHow to Use the NAIS Demographic CenterTop 5 Data Questions DASL Databook
DASL Insights
Market View
Assessment of Inclusivity and Multiculturalism (AIM)
GoalsMethodologyCompleting the Self-AssessmentCompleting the AIM Online Climate Survey AIM Survey Definitions
Statistical Tables
Facts at a Glance
Student Engagement Surveys
Resilience Surveys
NAIS COVID-19 Parent and Faculty/Staff Satisfaction Surveys
About
Close
About
Join NAIS
School MembershipSchool SubscriptionNAIS Supporter Program Association Membership
NAIS Benefits
Help Center
Maximize Your Membership
Member and Subscriber Logos
International Council Advancing Independent School Accreditation
NAIS Resources by Role
Events
NAIS Store
Close
NAIS Store
The NAIS Head Search Handbook
Help Center
Home
About
Legal and Privacy Information
NAIS Privacy Statement
Effective Date: 12/4/2020
At the National Association of Independent Schools (NAIS), we respect and are committed to protecting your privacy. In a rapidly changing and increasingly digitally connected world, NAIS is committed to transparency, privacy protection, and data security. We recognize that our primary responsibility is to meet your interests and needs as a member, affiliate, or friend of NAIS. We also want you to understand how we use your membership information and the choices you can make about the way your information may be collected and used.
The Information We Collect—Registration
In order to use certain features of our website, a user must first complete a registration form. During registration, a user is required to give contact information, such as name, email address, school or organization, and job title. This information is used to contact the user about the resources and services on our site in which they may have expressed interest. It is optional for you to provide additional information, such as demographic information, and additional personally identifiable information so that we can provide a more personalized experience.
The Information We Collect and Use—Orders
Whenever you place an order via this site or register for professional development, information will be requested on an order form. The information requested includes name and shipping address and financial information such as a credit card number and expiration date. This information is used to obtain payment from the appropriate clearinghouse and to fill customers' orders. NAIS does not process payments directly; we use a third-party vendor who focuses their energies on making such transactions safe and efficient for both you, the user, and organizations like NAIS. NAIS does not collect or hold your credit card or other specific payment information.
The Information We Collect and Use—Cookies and Similar Technologies
Cookies are small bits of data that a site or its service provider transfers to your computer through your browser that enables the site or service provider to recognize your browser and remember certain information about you. We and our partners may use cookies and other similar technologies (such as pixel tags, ad tags, and web beacons) to collect information to help us understand your interactions with the NAIS website, such as pages you have visited, content you have viewed, search queries you have run and information that you have seen.
NAIS does use Google Analytics (including Universal Analytics and Demographics and Interest Reporting) to improve its website. Google Analytics collects information on the NAIS website and other unrelated websites and apps over time. Third parties that support NAIS by providing non-advertising services, such as allowing you to share content or tracking aggregate usage statistics, (e.g., Google Analytics tracking and Google AdWords) may also use cookies and other technologies to collect similar information. Google Analytics does not collect personally identifiable information to share with NAIS or others, and NAIS will not share your personally identifiable information with Google Analytics or its partners unless we have received specific consent from you. If you are still worried, you can opt out of Google Analytics.
NAIS also partners with ad networks and other ad serving providers (“Advertising Providers”) that serve ads on behalf of us and others on non-affiliated websites and apps.  Some of those ads may be personalized, meaning that they are intended to be relevant to you based on information Advertising Providers collect about your use of the NAIS website and other non-affiliated sites or apps over time, including information about relationships among different browsers and devices.  This type of advertising is known as interest-based advertising.
You can visit the DAA Webchoices tool at www.aboutads.info to learn more about interest-based advertising and to opt out of this advertising on websites by companies participating in the DAA program.  If you delete your cookies or use a different browser, you may need to renew your opt-out choices exercised through the DAA Webchoices tool.  Note that opting out will not stop advertising from appearing in your browser.  It may make the ads you see less relevant to your interests.  Additionally, your browser may offer tools to limit the use of cookies or to delete cookies; however, if you use these tools, our website may not function as intended.
Third Parties and Links to Other Sites
NAIS takes care to ensure its users' privacy, but not every company has comparable policies. Other than NAIS's own sites, no site on the web is under NAIS's exclusive control, not even those sites to which we may provide links. Therefore, NAIS cannot assume any responsibility for any other site's content or practices. Providers of internet sites or services have separate data and privacy practices independent of NAIS that govern the manner in which they use the information that you provide to them. Many websites use cookies to recognize you when you return to their site; some sites require that you provide information before they allow you to enter; some automatically gather information when you visit, such as what operating system your computer runs, what type of web browser you use, what internet access provider you use, or what other web pages you visit; and sites vary greatly (from each other and from NAIS) with regard to how they use such information and to whom they disclose it. We encourage you to exercise care each time you are asked to provide personally identifiable information at a site whose privacy policies you don't know.
Even on NAIS's site, many of the features and much of the content is supplied by third-party vendors (or jointly by NAIS and one or more third parties), each of which has its own privacy policies and practices. You may be asked to provide personally identifiable information when you register for certain services or promotions on our site; in such cases, the information you provide may be collected and used by a third party rather than, or in addition to, NAIS. Our policy requires such third-party vendors to adhere to contractual obligations to protect the confidentiality of the personal information we share with them and to use it only to provide specific services on our behalf, notify you in advance if they intend to use information you provide for purposes unrelated to the services or promotions for which you sign up, and to give you the opportunity to choose not to use their service rather than share your information with them, but we cannot assume responsibility for their compliance with our policy.
To Share with Our Affiliates
We may share your Personal Information with our affiliates for the purposes described in this Privacy Policy.
To Protect the Rights of NAIS and Others
There may be instances when NAIS may disclose your information, including situations where NAIS has a good faith belief that such disclosure is necessary in order to: (i) protect, enforce, or defend the legal rights, privacy, safety, or property of NAIS; (ii) protect the safety, privacy, and security of users of NAIS or members of the public; (iii) protect against fraud or for risk management purposes; (iv) comply with the law or legal process; or (v) respond to requests from public and government authorities.
More on How We Use Information
(a) Financial—We use the financial information you provide about yourself when ordering a product or service, or registering for a conference to complete the transaction. We do not share this information with outside parties except to the extent necessary to complete the transaction. NAIS does not store this data in any way that is accessible to NAIS staff.
(b) Customization—We use the information we collect based on usage by those who register with NAIS to customize the information on the site to the user's interests.
(c) Identification—We use the identifying information you provide about yourself for the in-print and online membership directory, and for a variety of organizational purposes, including sharing with you information about NAIS products and services we think might be of interest to you. We offer postal mailing lists for rent to third parties, but we do not sell, rent, or share email addresses with external organizations or individuals.
(d) Surveys—We use data gathered through surveys and benchmarking studies solely for the purposes described therein. Unless specifically noted otherwise, no personally identifiable information is disclosed in reporting on these surveys and studies.
(e) Demographics—We use non-identifying and aggregate demographic information to better design our website and other NAIS services. We also may share such information with associations, organizations, and commercial enterprises to help them understand the makeup of the NAIS membership.
(f) Opting out—Finally, NAIS does not intend to use or share the personally identifiable information provided to us online in ways unrelated to the ones described above without also providing you an opportunity to opt-out or otherwise prohibit such unrelated uses. For information on opting out of other information gathering from Google Analytics, click here.
Public Forums
NAIS Connect and similar NAIS online forums make online communities available to NAIS’s users. As indicated above, please remember that any information that is disclosed in these areas becomes public information and you should exercise caution when deciding to disclose your personally identifiable information. NAIS online communities and other online services have separate use policies to which users must adhere.
Supplemental Information
This site supplements the information that you provide with information that is received from third parties. For example, we may include in your profile data supplied by the institution with which you are employed. As specified above, we do not share any personally identifiable information with Google Analytics or other third parties.
Our Commitment to Data Security
The security of your information is very important to us. NAIS implements a variety of security measures to maintain the safety of your Personal Information. However, due to the inherent open nature of the internet, no data transmission over the internet or any wireless network can be guaranteed to be secure. As a result, while we take measures to protect your Personal Information, we cannot ensure or guarantee the security of any information you send to us or that we store on our servers. Your use of the NAIS websites and related services demonstrates your assumption of this risk.
Updates to Privacy Policy
We may modify this Privacy Policy. Please look at the date below to see when this Privacy Policy was last revised. Any changes to this Privacy Policy will become effective when we post the revised Privacy Policy on the NAIS site. Policy changes will apply only to information collected on and after the date of the change.
How You Can Contact NAIS
You can email membership@nais.org for more information about any of the topics addressed here, including your data privacy.
You can send mail to the following postal address: NAIS, Attention: Membership & Community Engagement, 1129 20th Street, NW, Suite 800, Washington, DC 20036.
You can call the following telephone number: (202) 973-9700, and ask for the appropriate department.
Should you have other questions or concerns about these privacy policies or other aspects of our user agreement, please send us an email at membership@nais.org.
About NAIS
About the President
NAIS Governance
Annual Reports
Independent School Accreditation
Policy Positions
Vision and Values
History of NAIS
Schools in the News
Contact NAIS
Jobs at NAIS
Independent School Magazine
Fall 2020
Explore the new dimensions of health and well-being plus what these might look like for your school community.
Read More
Upcoming Events
NAIS Webinar: Weekly Trend Report: An Update on Enrollment Agreements
December 15, 2020
Online
NAIS Webinar: Managing Your Endowment in a Post-COVID-19 World (Sponsored by Permanens Capital Partners)
December 16, 2020
Online
More Events
Research & Data
Data and Analysis for School Leadership
Where do you stand? Use more than 30 years of independent school data to help you make the right choices for your school.
VISIT THE DASL WEBSITE
Search NAIS Directories
Find a School, Company, or Colleague
Looking for an independent school in your area? Does your school need a product or service? Browse our listings.
CHOOSE A DIRECTORY
Principles of Good Practice
Looking for PGPs?
The NAIS Principles of Good Practice for member schools define high standards and ethical behavior in key areas of independent school operations. The PGPs reflect the overall dedication to quality education that has always characterized independent schools.
Find a PGP
Participate
more
Close
Conferences
more
Close
Annual ConferencePeople of Color Conference
Close
Diversity Leadership InstituteInstitute for New HeadsLeadership Through PartnershipInclusive Schools Network InstituteEquity Design LabSchool Leadership Team ExperienceSchool Leadership Institute
Fellowship for Aspiring School Heads
Sponsorship & Advertising
Learn
more
Close
Independent Ideas Blog
Independent School Magazine
Independent Teacher
Principles of Good Practice (PGPs)
Resource Guides
more
Close
Start StrongPromote Great GovernanceGrow EnrollmentCultivate Diverse and Inclusive CommunitiesEnsure Financial SustainabilityRecruit and Retain Top TalentLead Through ChangeBuild an Effective TeamCreate Inspiring Places to LearnManage a CrisisFund the Future
Knowledge Center
Legal and Legislative Resources
more
Close
NAIS Legal News You Can UseNAIS Legal Advisories
Research Clearinghouse
NAIS Podcasts
more
Data and Analysis for School Leadership (DASL)
more
Close
About DASLSchool SurveysDemographicsHow to Use the NAIS Demographic CenterTop 5 Data QuestionsDASL Databook
DASL Insights
more
Close
Market View
Assessment of Inclusivity and Multiculturalism (AIM)
more
Close
GoalsMethodologyCompleting the Self-AssessmentCompleting the AIM Online Climate SurveyAIM Survey Definitions
School MembershipSchool SubscriptionNAIS Supporter ProgramAssociation Membership
NAIS Benefits
Help Center
Maximize Your Membership
Member and Subscriber Logos
International Council Advancing Independent School Accreditation
Events
NAIS Store
Help Center
Close
